B-B-Band Collab
Oligobeito
The Hamukitada
Chekera Babies
Shimo-Kitazawa
I'm just awful.
ダメね～
Oh... But you at least managed
to play it to the en—
あっ やっ…
でも 一応 最後まで弾けて…
About that, though!
そこなんだけどね！
Y-Yes?
は… はい
考えてみたら 私
ボーカルもやるわけじゃない？
I just realized, I'm supposed
to do vocals too, right?
でも 今は
全神経 ギターに行っちゃって
But I can't sing while I'm focusing
all my motor control on the guitar.
歌どころじゃなくて
な… なるほど
I... I see...
もういっそ ボーカルだけのほうが
I was thinking it might be better
for the band if I just sang...
バンドのためなんじゃないかと
思ったんだけど
But then I wouldn't have anything
to do during interludes,
でも 間奏中とか やることなくて
私 オロオロしちゃいそうだし…
and I'd probably start fidgeting on stage...
あっ えっと… イエイ！
Oh, um... Yeah!
So...
だから…
あっ
もっと頑張らないとね
I guess I'd better work harder!
Kit-aura!
キタ～ン！
うわっ
My eyes!
目が！
え？
N-Nothing.
い… いえ
Her eager self-improvement power
is too bright to look directly at!
爽やか向上心パワー
まぶしすぎる！
But are you sure it's all right
for me to sing?
そういえば
私がボーカルやってもいいの？
え？
そうだ 後藤さんも一緒に歌って
I know! You should sing with me!
N-N-Not happening!
むっ むむむむ… 無理です 絶対！
B-But...
え？　でも…
むむむむ…
N-N-N-N-N-N-N-N-N...
むむむむむ…
I'm sorry. Is it that unpleasant a thought?
ごめんなさい そんな嫌なのね
Hey, nice one.
いいね それ
ん？
新しいギターパフォーマンス？
Is that some new guitar showmanship move?
先輩！
これ好きですか？
Senpai!
Do you like it?
Then I'll practice it too!
じゃあ 私も練習を
You don't need to practice that.
しなくていい そんな練習
リョウも来たし 向こうに集合ね
Ryo's here, so let's meet up at the club!
はい！
むむむむ…
Right!
We will now begin the band meeting!
それでは
バンドミーティングを始めます
拍手！
Round of applause!
Now, here's today's topic!
さて 本日のお題は こちら
The question:
How can we be
more band-like?
ズバリ！
より一層
バンドらしくなるには？
How can we be more band-like?
おお～
It's so half-assed!
ざっくりしている！
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#04 Jumping Girl(s)
How can we be
more band-like?
Now that we've got a full member lineup,
せっかく
メンバーも集まったんだし
I figured the first order of business
was to get us acting more band-like!
まずは４人で より一層
バンドらしくなっていきたいなと
I... I see!
な… なるほど
I know practice is crucial,
いや 練習あるのみなのは
分かってるよ
but there's gotta be more to us than that!
だけど そればっかりだとね
いろいろ話したりするのも
大事かなって
I think we should talk
about all kinds of stuff!
もしかして 虹夏ちゃん
Is she trying to give Kita-san
a break from all her practice?
最近 練習 頑張ってる
喜多さんの息抜きに？
まずは形から入ってみるのも
ありでしょ？
One tactic is to nail the
superficial stuff first!
Oh, that totally works!
ありですね！
はやってるメイクとかも
Like if you start imitating a new popular
make-up technique and end up looking great!
まねしてるうちに
様になってくるというか
そうそう！
Exactly!
It's like they're speaking
a foreign language...
どうしよう 全然ピンとこない
というわけで…
And with that in mind...
とりあえず
バンドグッズ作ってきた！
I made us band merch!
予想以上に形から入ってきた！
That's a more superficial
starting point than I expected!
Did you just put a zip tie around your wrist?
それ ただ
結束バンド巻いてるだけじゃ…
えっ かわいくない？
いろんな色あるよ
Cute, huh? They come in all colors!
あっ
We'll sell them for 500 yen a piece.
物販で500円で売ろう
ぼったくり
What a ripoff!
650 if they're signed.
サイン付きは650円で
What a steal! I'll take one!
安い！　買います！
それじゃ バンド内で
お金が循環するだけでは？
Won't that just be circulating
money within the band?
Anyone else with ideas
for becoming more band-like?
ほかにバンドらしくなるアイデア
ある人～
I can set us up an Isstagram and run it!
もし イソスタとか
やるなら 私やります！
いいねえ！
ＳＮＳ大臣 任命します
Great idea!
I hereby appoint you
Minister of Social Media!
そのときが来たら
毎日 更新しますね
And I'll post every day when the time comes!
あとは～ ファンクラブの設立？
And...
What about forming a fan club?
すごく気が早い！
That's awfully hasty!
年会費は１万円
10,000 yen annual membership fee.
That's awfully expensive!
そして高い！
Membership perks include meet-and-greets
ファンクラブ
会員特典として
握手会と 年に１度
and a once-a-year takoyaki party with the band.
メンバーとの
たこ焼きパーティを…
材料はファン持ちで
The fans bring the ingredients.
安い！　入ります！
What a steal! I'll join!
Kita-chan, you're already in the band.
喜多ちゃんもメンバーだからね？
What about you, Gotoh-san?
後藤さんは？
えっ？
Any ideas?
何かアイデアある？
え… えっ？
What do I do? I wasn't even thinking!
どうしよ 何も考えてなかった
W-Well...
い… いや…
H-Her eyes are so sparkly!
な… なんか 目がキラキラしてる！
I feel the burden of expectation!
期待の目をされてる～
Um... Um...
えっと え～っと…
な… なんか言わなきゃ
I-If I don't say something, I... I...
Future
Society
Digital
Chiba
Memories
Passwords
Internet
Home Life
Outer Space
Old Books
New Stuff
Emotions
Part-
Time
Job
Dreams
Fukui
Laws
Identity
Life
Entertainment
Outer Space
Types of Fish
なんか なんか…
わああ～ 何も浮かばない！
Nothing's coming to mind!
ああ ぼっちちゃんは大丈夫
What do I... What do I...
Oh, Bocchi-chan can sit this one out.
えっ？
ぼっちちゃんには
オリジナルソングの作詞という
She has a more important job:
writing lyrics for our original song!
重要任務があるから
あ…
え？
We settled on it before, remember?
前に決めたじゃん
リョウが作曲
ぼっちちゃんが作詞って
Ryo would write the music,
and you'd write the lyrics!
If you've got off-limits words,
Bocchi-chan, you should write the lyrics!
歌詞に禁句が多いなら
ぼっちちゃんが書けばいいよ
write the lyrics!
書けばいいよ
書けばいいよ…
write the lyrics!
あ…
え～っ！
リョウ先輩の曲 楽しみです
Wow! I can't wait to hear
your song, Ryo-senpai.
もう作ってたりするんですか？
Have you written it already?
No.
ううん
イメージ湧いたら そのうち
I'll do it once I get inspiration.
わあ～ 楽しみ！
I just can't wait!
Go for it, Ryo!
頼むよ リョウ
それと作詞大臣
And Minister of Lyrics!
は… はい
R-Right...
後藤さん すごい仕事 任されて
かっこいいね
Gotoh-san, it's so cool that
you took on such a tough job!
C-Cool?!
か… かっこいい？
W-Well, I can write lyrics
like nobody's business!
あっ まあ作詞なんて朝メシ前
ちょちょいのちょいですよ
It's the super-easiest thing ever!
後藤さんって
すぐ調子乗っちゃうのね
You get carried away so easily, Gotoh-san.
エヘッ エヘヘ
大ヒット間違いなしの
I'm gonna write the most band-like lyrics
and guarantee us a huge hit!
バンドらしい歌詞
書いちゃいますから
フフッ フフフ
"Band-like"?
“らしい”…
ん？
ヘヘヘ ヘヘッ ヘへ…
One Week Later
な…
何も思いつかない…
I couldn't think of anything!
Shake!
Change paws!
I failed to write a single lyric,
but I've perfected my signature...
Gotoh
Hitori Gotoh
Gocchi
Bocchi
This
one!
Hitori
歌詞は１行も書けてないのに
Change, and pose!
サインは完成してしまった
Isn't it cool?
こ… こんなこと
してる場合じゃないのに！
Why can't I get my priorities in order?!
Jimihen's amazing!
わ～い
ワンワン
Futari!
ふたり～
I already spent five hours yesterday
editing video to escape reality.
昨日も現実逃避して
動画 ５時間も編集してしまったし
よし
Done.
I'm so stupid! I'm a paramecium!
ああ～ 私のバカ ゾウリムシ～！
ねえ 何書いてるの？
ワン
Whatcha writin'?
No!
あっ ちょ…
Here it is!
あった
中学のころ書いた作詞ノート
My lyrics notebook from middle school!
Lyrics
I've bought the ingredients for a voodoo doll
At 2:30 this morning I do the deed
5 inch nails  White Gown  Straw Doll
Mallet — All I need
The pain won't end in just seven days
Konk konk, konk konk  I drive it in
Konk konk, konk konk  It's 2 AM
Konk konk, konk konk  Here, all alone
Every day, alone, I curse you
Tremble in fear, la la la la...
5 inch nails          White Gown            Straw Doll
Mallet — All I need
The pain won't end in just seven days
呪詛？
A curse?
Ijichi
Energetic
Nice
Pretty
Gotoh
Social anxiety
Great at
compliments
Eats weeds
Doesn't talk
But not socially anxious
Yamada
Let's get organized.
整理しよう
Kita-san's gonna be singing this song.
この曲は喜多さんが歌う
Cheerful lyrics.
明るい歌詞… 青春ソングかな
A seishun song, maybe?
キタ～ン
Kit-aura!
I could easily write depressing lyrics,
of course...
暗い歌詞だったら
いくらでも書けるけど
Kit-aura!
キタ～ン！
うん
そんなの望まれてないだろうし
Nobody wants that,
キタ～ンとした バンドっぽいのを
so I've gotta write something band-like,
with real Kit-aura!
Put yourself in the mind
of cheery person!
明るい人間になりきるんだ！
フォ～！
I'm an extrovert!
私は陽キャ！
ナイトプールでサーフィンする女！
The woman who surfs in the pool at night!
そしてクイーン オブ ウェイの名を
我が物にする女！
The woman who claims the title Queen of Woot!
ウェイ ウェイ
ウェ～イ！　イッキ！　イッキ！
Woot! Woot! Woot!
Woot! Go! Go!
Let's get some vibes up in here!
バイブス上げてこ～っ！
おにいさん テキーラ追加～
Tequila shots in the house!
No! That's not a cheery person,
って 違う！
これは明るい人じゃなくて
ただのパリピだ！
it's just a party animal!
クウ～ン
No more shortcuts.
暗示じゃダメ
喜多さんに なりきろう
You must become Kita-san.
今日 渋谷行く人
この指 と～まれ！
Come over now if you wanna go to Shibuya!
ああ…
Everyone takes Isstaworthy pics right here!
ここは
有名なイソスタ映えスポット
あと10分後に
花火が打ち上がるから
They'll be launching fireworks in ten mins,
so let's take pictures together then!
みんなで写真を撮ろ…
え？
お母さんの知り合いに
いい霊媒師さんがいてね
I know an exorcist, if you need one...
It's n-n-n-not like that!
ごごごご… 誤解！
ワン
No Peeking
Okay, no seishun songs.
青春ソングは やめだ
応援ソングにしよう
Let's try a song of encouragement.
I personally find status-quo-affirming
lyrics annoyingly irresponsible, but...
本当は
無責任に現状を肯定する歌詞は
あまり好きじゃないんだけど
う～ん…
ん～
うう～
ううう～
we're all here
sending you
Your dreams will come true
Believe in yourself
It's so shallow...
薄っぺらい
Any depressed person hearing this song
would just drop deeper into despair!
こんな歌
落ち込んでるときに聞いたら
更に追い詰められる～
ん？
ひいっ！
F-F-Forgive me!
ゆゆゆ… 許してください！
Gotoh-san?
後藤さん？
えっ なになに どうした？
What's the matter now?
I-Isn't this an intervention
where you tear into me
ちょ… 調子に乗ったくせに
全然 歌詞書き上げてこない私を
I failed to write the lyrics I was assigned.
for failing to write lyrics
despite all the bragging I did?
呼び出して
つるし上げる会では？
That's perverse! No way!
そんな外道なことしないよ
Then why did you call us here?
じゃあ 今日 集まったのは…
I didn't think of it until now,
この前 思いつかなかったけど
まだあったんだよ
but there's one other really
band-like thing we can do!
バンドらしいこと
え？
アー写を撮ろう！
Take ProPhos!
ア… ？
Promotional photos, she means.
アーティスト写真だって
ああ～
今ある結束バンドのアー写には
ぼっちちゃん 写ってないしね
Since Bocchi-chan isn't in
Kessoku Band's current ProPho.
C-Current?
い… 今ある？
Want to see?
見る？
この前 ライブ出るために撮った
We took it for our last concert.
うっ…
I mean, since Kita-chan ditched us...
ほら 喜多ちゃん逃げちゃたから
I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい！
I've never seen such an awful ProPho.
こんなひどいアー写 初めて見た
So, because it's nice out today
and none of us have plans,
そんなわけで 今日は天気もいいし
みんなの予定も空いてたから
I figured we'd take a few ProPhos!
アー写 撮っちゃおうかなって
えっ！　そ… 外でですか？
O-Outside?!
We don't have the money
to rent a studio, so...
スタジオで撮るのは
お金がないから無理
Taking public pictures in Shimo-Kita
is too much to ask of a nerd like me!
下北の街なかで写真 撮るなんて
陰キャにはハードル高すぎる！
まあ 外じゃなくて
STARRYでもいいんだけど
We could do it in Starry
instead if you prefer,
but a ProPho is important
for conveying a band's direction
アー写って バンドの方向性とか
メンバーの特徴を
and the unique qualities of its members.
１枚で伝える 大切なものだからさ
So we really need to give it
everything we have?
じゃあ
気合い入れて撮らないとですね
Precisely!
そのとおり
We need something that'll have impact,
ライブハウスのサイト告知や
フライヤーや雑誌
whether it's in a club ad online,
a flyer, or a magazine!
どんなところで使われても
インパクトがある感じにしないと
What she said.
だそうだ
V-Very well.
わ… 分かりました　覚悟決めます
I resign myself to this fate.
Resign yourself?
覚悟？
I declare this ProPho-scouting journey on!
よ～し
アー写撮影の旅に レッツラゴー！
Let's la go!
Yeah!
お～っ
お～
Yeah...
Stairs...
階段　フェンス　植物の前
A fence...
With plants...
At the park...
そして 公園…
I think we've covered all the bases
for broke band ProPhos...
金欠バンドマンのアー写で
定番どころは こんなところかな
Oh, and an evocative wall!
あっ あと良さげな壁！
Milkus Water
I wish we'd brought our instruments.
今日 楽器
持ってくればよかったわね
あ～ た… 確かに
G-Good point...
楽器持ってたほうが
更に かっこよくなりそうですけど
Having our instruments
might make us look cooler.
For you guys, maybe.
君たちはね
え？
絵になるのはギターとベースだけで
Only guitarists and bassists
look cool that way.
ドラムは
かわいそうなことになるんだよ
What about the poor drummer?
I'm stuck just holding up my drumsticks!
手に持つのは
ドラムスティックだけだよ？
かわいいじゃん
But that's cute.
Then let's swap instruments, just for today!
じゃあ 今日だけ楽器 交換しよ
Nah, that's lame.
かっこ悪いからやだ
ううう～！
あっ…
あっ こことかどうです？
What about here?
Isn't it nice?
良くないですか？
With all these posters up, it has
a real "Shimo-Kitazawa" vibe!
たくさん
ポスターとか貼ってあって
下北沢らしいというか
そこ 前まで
よく行ってたＣＤショップだった
That used to be a CD shop I went to a lot.
Huh?
えっ？
Lots of record shops and club venues
closing these days, yeah.
レコードショップも
ライブハウスも
どんどん なくなるね～
昔ながらの店が
どんどん消えていく
Shops that have been there for decades,
disappearing one by one...
あっ あの…
なんだか ごめんなさい
I-I'm really sorry...
Ryo, you were just celebrating
that new book store.
リョウ 新しい本屋 出来て
喜んでたじゃん
Yeah. I love B&C.
うん　Ｂ＆Ｃ 好き
Kita-chan, don't let Ryo jerk you around.
喜多ちゃん　リョウに
振り回され過ぎないようにね
Ninety percent of the things she says
are more or less just for vibes.
その場のノリで話してること
９割だから
でも 先輩になら
むしろ振り回されたい
But Senpai can jerk me around
any time she wants!
きゃあ～！
ええ…
Um?
うおっ
あっ なんだ ぼっちちゃんか
Oh, it's just Bocchi-chan.
U-Um...
あっ あの…
I-I thought I saw a
n-nice-looking wall over there...
あっちに た… 多分ですけど
良さげな感じの壁が…
Hey, great work!
おお でかした！
Taking it now!
それじゃあ 撮るよ～
う～ん
We're definitely capturing everyone's
personalities, but it's not really band-like.
メンバーのキャラは出てるけど
いまいちバンド感が…
Isn't there a way to really
make it scream "band"?
バンドっぽさを感じる要素が
欲しいな～
“バンドマンのお手本たる存在”
こと私の表情を まねしてみて
As I am the quintessential musician,
you need only mimic my expression.
I'd love to know where you
get all that confidence...
ホント どこから来るの？
その自信
But we can't go wrong doing what Senpai says!
でも 先輩の言うとおりにすれば
間違いなんてないですよ
Right, Gotoh-san?
ねっ？　後藤さん
Y-Yes...
あっ はい
A pair of yes-men, huh?
イエスマンが２人…
分かったよ
Fine, we'll do it.
なんか お通夜みたい
ですね
Looks like we're at a funeral.
Yeah...
にしても 喜多ちゃんは
どの写真もかわいいね
But Kita-chan looks cute in any pic we take!
Aw, no I don't!
そんなことないですよ
Sure you do!
あるある　なんていうか
写真慣れしてるっていうか
It's almost like you know what you're doing.
Oh, I guess it's because I upload pics
to Issta all the time!
ああ それは よくイソスタに
写真上げるからかも
See?
ほら
おお～ さっすがＳＮＳ担当大臣
That's our Minister of Social Media!
うっ
Bocchi-chan's dying!
ぼっちちゃんが瀕死状態に！
What's wrong, Gotoh-san? Stay with us!
後藤さん どうしたの？
死なないで！
Oh, no! She's flopping around like a fish!
いやだ すごいピクピク…
I've never taken pictures
with friends before.
友達と写真なんて
一度も撮ったことない
What do I do? Please, wake up!
Since... I never had friends before.
だって 友達いなかったから
The only pictures I've taken
that weren't with family
家族以外と撮った写真は
クラスの集合写真くらい
were class pictures.
With those as my only proof of existence
for the past fifteen years...
15年 生きてきた証しが
それしかない私って…
Look at Bocchi-chan's weird face!
ぼっちちゃん 顔ヤバいって
現代の女子高生で
私みたいな人 ほかにいるのかな
I wonder if there are any other
high school girls like me still around?
Perhaps I've become a rare species,
on par with the tsuchinoko?
ツチノコと肩を並べるくらいの
希少種なのでは？
I am... I am the tsuchinoko
of Shimo-Kitazawa.
私が… 私が下北沢のツチノコです
Gotoh-san's saying the strangest things!
後藤さんが変なこと言ってる！
Nah, this is normal for her.
いつも こんなんだよ
Noko-noko. Noko-noko.
うん
ノコノコ…
Bocchi-chan, why don't you
start your own Isstagram?
ぼっちちゃんも
イソスタ始めてみたら？
What do you think, Minister?
ねえ？　大臣も そう思うでしょ？
ぜひ！
Totally!
Let's become friends!
友達になりましょ
If we're going to be a band,
バンド活動していくなら
we should really have
individual member accounts!
メンバー個人のアカウント
あったほうがいいと思うし
後藤さん！
Gotoh-san?!
If I were to get an account...
私がアカウントなんて持ったら…
ただでさえ根暗なのに
バンドやって⸺
Someone with self-esteem so bad
she's already trying to form a band
人気者になろうとしてる
こじらせ人間なのに
to get popular despite
total social ineptitude...
そんな私が
そんなもの始めてしまったら…
If s-someone like me were to
start an account like that...
You would witness the birth of...
生まれてしまう！
承認欲求モンスター！
The attention-whore monster!
Like my posts!
いいね くれ～！
My video site is all I need.
私には動画サイトだけあればいい
Gotoh-san!
後藤さ～ん！
あ…
Bocchi-chan!
ぼっちちゃ～ん
We won't push you to get on social media anymore!
Please come back to us!
ＳＮＳは もういいから
戻ってきて～！
ハッ！
You okay?
大丈夫？
Y-Yes...
あっ はい
フウ～
じゃあ アー写撮影 再開ね
Okay, back to the ProPhos!
う～ん
なかなか いいの決まんないね
Nothing's really hitting the spot...
Hey, what about a jump pic?
あっ！
ジャンプとか どうですか？
Jump pic?
ジャンプ？
It's really photogenic, and it could
bring out everyone's personality!
絵になるし
みんなの素の感じ 出そうですけど
Great idea! You're a genius, Kita-chan!
それ いい！　喜多ちゃん天才～
A wise man once said,
有識者が言っていた
any anime where they jump in
the OP is a god-tier anime.
オープニングでジャンプする
アニメは神アニメと
え？
Would jumping in our ProPho
thus make us a god-tier band?
つまり アー写でジャンプすれば
神バンドになるのでは？
Where is she getting that from?
何が“つまり”なんだろう？
I'm not sure I followed your logic there...
全然 意味分かんないんだけど…
But let's give it a try!
とりあえず やってみよう！
あっ えっ…
Five, four, three,
５ ４…
I c-can't even remember
the last time I jumped!
ジャ… ジャンプとか
記憶にないくらいしてない！
two, one!
あっ わわっ
Oh, I see Bocchi's undies.
あっ ぼっちのパンツが
Wow, that's one hell of a picture!
とんでもない写真
撮れちゃったな～
I'm sorry for putting something
so worthless in the picture.
無価値なものを写して
すみません
Please delete it.
消してください
I was hoping for a cuter reaction there...
もっと かわいい反応
期待してたのに…
If I can't even jump properly, I'm...
ジャンプすら
満足にできない私って…
ほ～ら もう１回 いくよ！
Okay, let's try one more!
Awesome! It's got the band feel
and the seishun thing going!
いいね～
バンド感に青春っぽさが
プラスされたね！
Do you think I could get
a copy of that picture?
写真のデータ
もらっていいですか？
M-Me too!
あっ 私も！
うん バンドらしくなってきた
Yeah, we're feeling band-like now!
I feel like we're one step closer
to becoming a popular band!
人気バンドへの夢に
また一歩 近づいたね
R-Right!
はっ はい！
Kessoku Band is getting started for real!
結束バンド 本格始動ですね！
Okay!
よ～し 夏にライブと
We'll have our concert in summer (TBD),
our demo CD sale (TBD),
デモＣＤ配布して
our first album release in winter (TBD),
冬にファーストアルバム
リリース！
and become Shimo-Kitazawa's own
good vibes-iest vibes-band!
下北沢発祥のエモエモな
エモロックバンドになるぞ～
Sounds like there's a lot
still to be decided!
確定情報が何ひとつないですね！
アハハッ 確かに
まだ曲も出来てないのに
Good point!
We don't even have a song yet!
あっ
I t-totally forgot about the lyrics!
さ… 作詞のこと
すっかり忘れてた！
Of course, we've got Ryo and
Bocchi-chan on the case, so...
まあ ここは
リョウとぼっちちゃんに
頑張っていただいて
Hey, where's Ryo?
って あれ？　リョウは？
She must have disappeared.
気付いたら もう…
What a total free spirit!
ホント自由なんだから
Anyway, thanks for coming today!
じゃあ 今日は ありがとね
解散～
Dismissed!
The more time that passes,
Lyrics
時間がたてば たつほど
the higher the lyrics bar seems to rise.
歌詞のハードルが
上がっていく気がする
こ… これ見せて
冷たい反応されたら…
I-If I show them this and
they're mean to me...
O-Or worse, if they're
obviously humoring me, I...
いや 気を遣われて
励まされたりとかしたら 私…
M-Maybe I should show it to
someone and see how they react.
い… 一旦 誰かに見せて
様子を見よう
Ryo-san, maybe.
リョウさんかな
I don't think Ryo-san would ever humor me.
リョウさん 気とか使わなそうだし
Ryo
a
It's a pleasure to make contact with you
This is Bocchi speaking
If you happen to still be in Shimo-Kita,
do you think you might be able to
consider having a look at my lyrics?
Read
あっ もう既読 付いた
She already read it!
I'm here, come by
ん？
わっ！
Huh?
お… おしゃれカフェ
A t-trendy café!
Congratulations
on Opening
Congrats on opening
Congrats, La Chic
Congratulations, La Chic
が… 外食なんて
一度も一人でしたことない
I've never been to a real
restaurant by myself.
I can't even enter a convenience store
without psyching myself up in advance.
コンビニだって それなりに
気合い入れないと 入れないのに
Congrats on opening
い… いきなり入っていいのかな
A-Am I allowed to just walk in?
How do people just walk into places?
どうやって入るんだっけ？
ドラマとかで どうしてた？
How do they do it on TV and stuff?
Oh, I know!
あっ 確か…
あっ へ… へい 大将 やってる～？
Are ya winning, diners?
Oh, Bocchi.
あ… ぼっち　こっちこっち
Over here.
Th-This is awkward.
き… 気まずい
Come to think of it, I've never
been alone with Ryo-san before.
そういえば リョウさんと
２人っきりで会うのは初めてかも
I don't even know much about her.
いまいち どういう人か知らないし
F-For that matter, why hasn't
she talked to me yet?
というか なんで
全然 しゃべってくれないんだろ
ごちそうさまでした
That was delicious.
She finished eating!
た… 食べ終わってる！
What do I do? Should I initiate?
えっ ど… どうしよう
私から切り出せばいいのかな
But...
いや でも…
That photo shoot sure was fun, huh?!
さっきの撮影 楽しかったですね！
Not really.
別に
That could be the result!
って なるかもしれないし！
うう… うぐぐ…
Just show me the lyrics.
早く歌詞 見せて
あっ はい
Oh, right.
Thank you.
お願いします
うむ 拝読いたす
No problem. Let's see.
Oh, ohh!
おっ おお～っ！
She's unusually flustered!
珍しく うろたえてる？
This is good.
これでいいんだ？
えっ？
I'm not sure I agree,
but for the band's sake...
うう～ よくはないけど
バンドのことを考えると…
Yes, it's a masterpiece.
あっ はい　傑作です
うん
個人的に このサインは
Gotoh
Hitori Gotoh
Gocchi
Bocchi
This
one!
Hitori
Though personally I think one
is a bit childish for a band.
ロックバンドにしては
子供っぽい気がする
That's not the right page!
そのページじゃないです
Are you personally satisfied
with these lyrics, Bocchi?
ぼっち的には この歌詞で満足？
Oh, w-well...
えっ あっ え… それは
I figured we should do something
really "hit band"-like...
ヒットしたバンドらしいのが
いいのかな～と…
Can't do it anymore
You say as you give up on moving forward
On a road that seems to go on forever
It feels like you'll never arrive anywhere
And that's got you worried, doesn't it?
But hey now, listen up
Don't forget you're not alone, that we're all here
We're sending you this cheer just as your heart's about to break
Your dreams will come true
Don't give up until the very end!
Believe in yourself the way you are
Believe in yourself and get walking again!
Glory awaits you ahead, I know it
For everyone around the world trying hard, Go for it!
Did I ever tell you?
言ったっけ？
I was in another band a long time ago.
私 昔は
別のバンドにいたんだ
そのバンドの青臭いけど
まっすぐな歌詞が好きだったんだ
Their lyrics were awkward,
but I liked how honest they were.
でも 売れるために必死になって
But, desperate for sales, they started
going in a more commercial direction.
どんどん歌詞を売れ線にして
それが嫌になったから辞めたんだ
I hated that. That's why I quit.
We had a little fight about it at the time.
辞めるときも
ちょっと もめたりして…
あ…
And just as I was feeling sick
of the whole band thing...
バンドそのものが
嫌になってたころ…
ねえ 暇ならベースやって
Hey.
If you've got time,
will you play bass for me?
Why?
なんで？
Because I love the way you play!
だって あたし
リョウのベース 好きだし
When Nijika said that to me, I decided
to give playing in a band another try.
そう虹夏に言われて
もう一度
バンドやってみようかなって
Abandoning your uniqueness
is equivalent to dying.
個性 捨てたら
死んでるのと一緒だよ
Ryo-san?
リョウさん？
だから いろいろ考えて
つまんない歌詞書かないでいいから
So don't write generic lyrics
based on other concerns.
Write what you want to write.
ぼっちの好きなように書いてよ
あ…
B-But if I do that, I'll write bitter,
social-outcast lyrics—
け… けど そうすると
根暗で どんよりな歌詞が…
But won't it be hilarious
if a normie sings that?
でも それ リア充っ子に歌わせたら
面白くない？
え？
毎日１人 呪っていくね
I spend my days cursing you losers!
Bringing a wide variety of individuals
together into one sound...
バラバラな個性が集まって
ひとつの音楽になって
それが
結束バンドの色になるんだから
That's the color that Kessoku Band will have.
あっ
Ryo-san is actually a considerate person.
リョウさん
ちゃんとした人だったんだ
Let's get out of here.
そろそろ出よう
あっ はい
R-Right!
Oh, Ryo-san...
えっ あっ リョウさん
The check...
お会計…
Sorry, I'm broke. Treat me?
ごめん
今 お金ないから おごって
Wh-What?
えっ？　で… でも
B-But you're the one who invited me...
リョ… リョウさんが
ここに誘ったんじゃ…
I just couldn't take another
day of eating weeds.
最近 草しか食べてなくて限界で
You're still doing that?!
まだ野草生活を！
And this shop just opened,
and I wanted to eat here so bad...
それに この店
オープンしたばっかりだし
どうしても食べたくて
お願い おごって
Please, treat me?
I t-take back what I said!
ぜ… 前言撤回
本当に ごめん　来月返します
I really am sorry.
I'll pay you back next month.
N-No need to rush...
あっ いつでも大丈夫なので
あっ あの！
U-Um...
ん？
わ… 私 頑張ります！
I-I'm going to try my best!
Sure. Can't wait to see it.
うん　じゃあ 楽しみにしてるよ
フウ…
フフッ
U-Um...
あっ あの…
あっ…
I f-finished the lyrics...
歌詞 出来たんですけど
H-Here.
ど… どうぞ
後藤さん 目のクマ 大丈夫？
Gotoh-san, are you all right? You look tired.
I'm fine.
あっ はい
I've just been so focused on the lyrics,
ここのところ作詞に夢中になって
その… 寝るの忘れたりして
I c-completely forgot to sleep...
Wow!
おお～
Let's have a look!
どれどれ　ぼっちちゃんの力作
拝見しましょ～
I can't wait to see the
fruits of your labors!
It m-might be... too much of a downer.
あの く… 暗すぎるかも
確かに暗いね
It certainly is a downer.
リョウ先輩！
Ryo-senpai!
But it's very Bocchi.
でも ぼっちらしい
あっ
少ないかもしれないけど
誰かに深く刺さるんじゃないかな
It might not connect with too many people,
but those it does, it'll hit deeply.
あ…
ウヘッ
フッ
エヘッ
エヘヘッ
フフフ…
Where'd this friendship come from?!
なんで急に
仲良くなってるの？
But these lyrics really are
super great, Bocchi-chan!
でもさ この歌詞
ホントにいいよ ぼっちちゃん
I love this phrase here!
あっ！
私 ここのフレーズ 好きです
Same.
私も
エヘッ エヘヘヘ…
I m-managed to figure out the lyrics.
か… 歌詞も なんとか形になった
I'm going to do my best...
頑張ろう
I hope the band can
stay together forever...
それで バンドがずっと続いて
and I can get lots of
pictures with everyone.
これからも みんなと いろんな写真
撮っていけたらいいな
ウヘヘヘヘへ
I sleep, with big problems
weighing down on me
Though you can’t beat that feeling
of being loved, it’s true
When I awaken from cold dreams,
my body feels numb
You shine so brightly,
it could make me a shadow
It’s time to take that step
Though there’s nothing certain about it
It carries my childish heart into tomorrow
It’s time to blast out the thoughts
rattling around in my brain
And live, to its fullest, a life
I’ve been taking advances on for so long
But I also love the days I spend
lying around, doing nothing
So I know I’m going to go see you
Before it all disappears some day
#05 Flightless Fish
Watch it.
見てください